（チヨ）覚悟！
Prepare yourself!
（はたけカカシ）ぬぬっ？
（チヨ）はあーっ！
（うずまきナルト）うぐっ…
Why you--!
この！
ぬわっ！
（テマリ）はっ
（バキ）あっ
（エビゾウ）んっ
カカシ先生に いきなり
何すんだってばよ
What do you mean by suddenly
pouncing on Kakashi-sensei like that?!
You wrinkly old hag!
このシワくちゃババア
This old hag... is good...
（ナルト）このババア…
できる
あのときは よくも…
I'll never forget what
you did back then!
White Fang of the Leaf,
木こノ葉はの白い牙め
I shall avenge my son's death
by defeating you today!
息子の敵 今こそ
わしが成敗してくれる
（カカシ）ああ いや 私は…
Er... no, you see... I'm...
No questions or answers!
（チヨ）問答無用じゃ
Nee-chan...
Take a good look at him!
（エビゾウ）姉ちゃんよ よく見ろよ
はっ？
（カカシ）アッハハ…
（エビゾウ）よく似とりはするが
He resembles him closely,
but this one is not the White Fang!
こいつは 白い牙ではねえよ
はあ？
Huh?
（カカシ）どうも
Uh... hello...
（エビゾウ）
それに 木ノ葉の白い牙は
Moreover, the White Fang
of the Leaf died long ago.
とうの昔に死んどる
（カカシ）アハハ
（エビゾウ）知らせを受けたとき
Remember?
When you got word of it,
you cried tears of regret,
‟息子の敵が討てなんだ”と
泣いて悔しがっておったろうが
since you could not avenge
your son.
（チヨ）うう…
Isn't that so, Nee-chan?
（エビゾウ）のう 姉ちゃん
Gotcha, I was only pretending
to have gone senile.
（チヨ）な～んてな ボケたふり
アハッ アハッ… アハハハ…
（ナルト）なっ あ…
（カカシ）あ～
（テマリ･春野はるのサクラ）ああ…
（カンクロウ）
ぐああー！ ぐあっ…
うあっ ああ…
Kankuro!
（バキ）カンクロウ
Let me have a look.
（サクラ）診させてもらいます
Please do.
（テマリ）頼む
Kakashi-sensei and the rest of you,
please stand back a bit.
カカシ先生たちは
少し離れていてください
Got it.
分かったってばよ
ハア ハア…
ああっ！
H-Hey! You're...?
（医療忍者）お… おい お前は…
I'm a Leaf Medical Ninja.
木ノ葉の医療忍者です
♪～
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
junbi iize are you ready
I'm ready, are you ready?
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Hold up your fingers and count down.
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
Are you ready for a few risks?
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
The rising cheers will become your courage.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
～♪
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Hold up your fingers and count down.
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
The Medical
Ninja's Student
They seem to have used
a heavy metal-based toxin.
（サクラ）重金属系の毒が
使われたようですね
It's the type that acts upon
the muscles to destroy the cells.
筋肉に作用して
細胞を破壊するタイプです
（チヨ）ほう
Just from that brief examination...
（医療忍者）あれだけの診察で…
You could tell that much...
（医療忍者）そこまで
His medical record please.
（サクラ）カルテを
Ah, here it is.
ああ これだ
This is the list
of toxic ingredients.
こっちが毒の成分表だ
There are blank spaces here
and there, but...
ところどころ 空欄もあるが
大体は予測できます
I can predict the general outcome.
The cardiac muscle
will be destroyed,
心臓の筋肉が破壊されて
and the heart could stop beating
at any time, so...
いつ停止しても
おかしくない状態ですから
It's difficult to say whether
we can concoct an antidote in time...
今から解毒薬を調合しても
間に合うかどうか
そんな… なんとかならないのか！
You don't mean that!
Isn't there anything we can do?
Please assemble the items
I request immediately.
すぐに 私が言うものを
そろえてください
Roger!
（医療忍者）はい
It's quite a crude treatment, but
it's the only option we have left.
（サクラ）
かなりの荒療治になりますが
１つだけ手があります
（我愛羅があら）ああ…
うっ ああ…
しっかりと押さえといてください
Hold him down firmly,
as this will be
a very delicate operation.
とてもデリケートな
作業になりますから
- Right.
- Understood.
（バキ）ああ
（テマリ）分かった
Here... goes...
いきます んっ！
（カンクロウ）ううっ
うわああ！ うっ…
Hold him down firmly!
（サクラ）しっかり押さえて
（一同）はい
- Yes!
I'll cause the Chakra
to flow into his body...
（サクラ）
チャクラを体に流し込んで
It will cause the toxin to
surface from the cells.
（サクラ）
毒を細胞から浮き上がらせる
It will then be absorbed
by this liquid...
それを溶液に吸着させ
and extracted!
引き抜く
（医療忍者･バキ）あっ
So that's the toxin...
あれが毒なのか
Yes!
（サクラ）よし
Next!
次
- Yes!
（医療忍者たち）はい
Say... Kakashi-sensei...
なあ カカシ先生
Huh?
（カカシ）ああ？
What sort of person was
that White Fang of the Leaf
さっき
このばあちゃんが言ってた...
that this old lady here
was talking about?
木ノ葉の白い牙ってどんな人？
（チヨ）ん？
Well, that's hard to say...
（カカシ）どんなと言われても
Hmm, let's see...
そうだな
Well, in a word...
まっ ひと言で言うと…
He was my father.
俺の父親だ
なっ
Hey, you there...
お… お主
白い牙の息子か
Are you the son
of the White Fang?
Yes...
（カカシ）はあ…
どうりで… よく似とるわけじゃ
But of course...
So that's why you look
so much like him...
（カカシ）アッハハハ…
（カンクロウ）うっ うう…
ああ… あっ
うああ！ うっ…
- Next!
- Yes!
（サクラ）次
（医療忍者）はい
ハア
I directly extracted the toxin.
直接 毒抜きをしました
With this, his life should
no longer be in danger.
これで 命の心配は
いらないと思います
（一同）おおっ
（ナルト）さすが サクラちゃん
Way to go, Sakura-chan!
ハァ ハァ
ハァ ハア…
ハア
But we still can't rest easy.
ですが まだ安心できません
I will now concoct an antidote
for the traces of toxin
これから僅かですが
体内に残留している毒に対する
解毒薬を調合します
that remain in his body.
Got it.
（バキ）分かった
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to ask.
必要なものがあれば
遠慮なく言ってくれ
Well then, first, I need a list
of the medicinal herbs
（サクラ）
では まずこの里で手に入る
薬草の一覧か何かを
that can be found in this village,
or something like that...
I'll bring it.
持ってきます
Please replace all of
his bandages.
包帯は 全て取り替えてください
Yes.
はい
And then prepare an IV drip.
それから点滴の用意を
Yes.
（医療忍者）はい
Also, please set aside a small amount
of the extracted toxin.
あと 抜き出した毒は
少量 抽出しておいてください
I will need it later.
あとで必要になりますので
Sakura-chan... You're so cool.
（ナルト）サクラちゃん
格好いいってばよ
（さくら）ハァ
You're just like the Slug Girl.
（チヨ）
まるでナメクジ娘のようじゃの
To think that a girl just
like you would come here...
ちょうど お前のような
おなごが来るとは
Yes, Tsunade-sama is my master.
はい
綱手つなで様は 私の師匠ですから
And besides, I was told by
my master to come here.
それに 私は師匠に言われて
ここへ来たんです
Here is the list of medicinal herbs.
（医療忍者）薬草のリストです
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Say Nee-chan... Time is flowing slowly,
but it's flowing.
姉ちゃんよ
時は ゆっくり流れているでよ
Hey! Takamaru has returned!
（砂すなの里さとの忍）
おい タカ丸まるが帰ってきたぞ
Baki-sama, a reply
has come from Leaf Village.
（砂の里の忍）バキ様
木ノ葉の里より返書です
Thank you for your troubles.
（バキ）ご苦労
It's from Hokage-sama.
火影ほかげ様からだ
What's Granny Tsunade saying?!
（ナルト）
綱手のばあちゃん なんだって？
It says that Guy's squad has been
sent here as a reinforcement unit.
（カカシ）
ガイの班を増援部隊として
こちらに送ったそうだ
な…
Bushy Brow-sensei's squad...?
ゲキマユ先生の班か
ハハッ
I'll bet everyone has gotten stronger.
みんな 強くなってんだろうな
They even said that Neji
has become a Jonin.
ネジなんか もう上忍じょうにんだっていうし
よーし 俺たちってば
のんびりしてらんねえ
All right!
Now's no time for us to just
be hanging around!
We should go after the Akatsuki...
right now!
すぐにでも 暁あかつきを追うってばよ
Going after him is
fine and well...
（カカシ）追うのはいいけど
But do you know where
those guys have gone to?
連中がどこに行ったか
分かってるの？
（ナルト）ま…
うん…
Um, excuse me for inquiring,
（カカシ）あの
ちょっとお聞きしたいんですが
but what is the follow-up
to the Akatsuki pursuit?
その後 暁の追跡は
どうなってるんです？
First, Kankuro set off by himself
and ended up like that.
（バキ）
まず 最初にカンクロウが
単独で出ていって ああなった
その後 追跡部隊を出したが
まだ連絡はない
Next, a tracking unit was sent out,
but they've yet to contact us.
Judging from the situation,
it's likely that...
状況から考えて おそらく…
One of the other village chiefs
has gone missing.
ほかに 里の上役が１名
行方不明になっている
I don't like to think that
he could be taken out so easily, but...
簡単にやられることはないと
思いたいのだが…
Then, you mean to say
you've completely lost sight of him?
（カカシ）では 完全に
見失ったということですか
Yes, that is so.
ああ そうだ
Baki-sama!
（医療忍者）バキ様
（バキ）ん？
Kankuro has awoken!
カンクロウが目を覚ましました
（バキ･ナルト）あ…
Kankuro, are you all right?!
（テマリ）カンクロウ 大丈夫か？
What, you're back already... Temari?
（カンクロウ）なんだよ…
もう帰ってきたのかよ テマリ
I heard the village was in crisis.
（テマリ）里の危機だと聞いてな
（カンクロウ）
心配かけて… すまねえな
Sorry... for making you worry.
（テマリ）バカ
You fool, don't talk
such nonsense!
くだらないこと言うな
Please lead me to the place
where Kankuro did battle.
（カカシ）カンクロウ君の
戦った場所まで案内してください
（バキ）あっ
I may not look it,
but I'm a pro at tracking...
（カカシ）
こう見えても 私 追跡のプロでして
少しでも ヤツらのにおいが
残っていれば…
If just the slightest trace
of their scent remains...
There's no need of that.
（カンクロウ）その必要はないぜ
うっ ああ…
My puppets... have all been recovered,
haven't they?
俺の傀儡くぐつは…
全部 回収してあるよな
I never imagined I'd find
this assortment
（サクラ）まさか砂隠すながくれにも
ここまで薬草がそろってるなんて
思ってもみなかった
of medicinal herbs here
in the Hidden Sand.
Still, the soil is not well suited
to growing medicinal herbs...
それでも 土地柄
なかなか薬草も育ちにくくて
In particular, we only have
a small amount of "Scurvy Grass".
特に友知草ともしりそうが僅かしか
No, this much is plenty.
（サクラ）
いいえ これだけあれば十分
I can make at least three antidotes.
解毒薬が３つは作れます
The enemy force was two
in number.
（カンクロウ）敵は２人
One of them led Gaara away...
１人は 我愛羅を連れてる
All you have to do is follow
Gaara's scent.
我愛羅のにおいを追えばいい
もし ２手に別れたとしても
Even if they split up into two,
one of them...
もう１人は… ぐっ
His smell is on that one...
そいつに においがついてる
In Crow's hand...
カラスの手に
服の１部を握らせておいた
I left him holding a scrap
of his clothes...
Even if you fall,
you won't fall without a fight...
（カカシ）
転んでもただでは起きない
Just what I'd expect from
a Sand Shinobi.
さすがは 砂の忍しのび
うわっ ぐっ…
Kankuro! Are you all right?
カンクロウ 大丈夫か
Y-Yeah...
ん…
Ah, he came all the way
from Hidden Leaf Village for us.
（テマリ）ああ 木ノ葉から
わざわざ来てくれたんだ
Uzumaki... Naruto... is it?
（カンクロウ）うずまきナルトか
Hey...
押忍
I see...
（カンクロウ）そうか
Summoning Jutsu!
（カカシ）口寄くちよせの術
Eight Ninja Dogs,
at your service!
（パックン）八忍犬はちにんけん ただいま見参けんざん
Pakkun!
パックン
Hey! Is that you, Naruto?!
Long time no see.
（パックン）おお ナルトか
久しぶりじゃな
Pakkun, you haven't changed a bit,
have you?
パックン ちっとも変わってねえな
You haven't either.
お主もな
Eh?! I've grown quite a bit taller.
（ナルト）え… ええっ！
いや 身長だって
ほら ずいぶん伸びたってばよ
Yes, yes, but enough
of this chatter.
（カカシ）はいはい
おしゃべりは そのくらいにして
I need you to get to work
right away!
すぐに働いてもらうよ
I want you to determine
which way he headed.
そいつが どこに向かったか
突き止めるんだ
Now, go!
行け
We'll contact you right away
when we find something.
はい 分かったらすぐ連絡する
We're counting on you.
（ナルト）頼むってばよ
All right!
（ナルト）よーし！
When Pakkun and the others
get back,
パックンたちが戻ってきたら
出発だってばよ
we're heading out, I tell you!
We've got to make preparations
right away...
すぐに準備を…
（カカシ）ナルト ちょい待ち
Naruto, wait a minute!
ん？
Kankuro...!
（チヨ）カンクロウよ
（カンクロウ）あっ
Grandmother Chiyo?
Grandfather Ebizo, too?!
チヨバア様にエビゾウじい様
I want to hear it one more time,
directly from your mouth...
もう１度 お前の口から
直接 聞きたい
There is no mistake that one
of the two enemies was Sasori.
２人の敵のうち
１人がサソリであったことは
Is that correct?
間違いないのじゃな
うう…
どうなのよ カンクロウ
What about it, Kankuro?
ああ
Yeah... It was Sasori
of the Red Sand.
赤砂あかすなのサソリだと
みずから そう言った
He said so himself.
Sasori of the Red Sand,
you say?
（カカシ）赤砂のサソリですか
We might be able to find out more
about Akatsuki.
暁について
もう少し詳しく聞けそうですね
Please...
お願いします
It's ready...
できた
（医療忍者たち）おおっ
Be sure to drink it all down...
ちゃんと全部 飲んで
（カンクロウ）ううっ…
があっ
You should be all right now, I think.
（サクラ）
これで もう大丈夫だと思います
Just lie there and rest for
a while without moving
あとは しびれが引くまで
動かないで
ゆっくり寝ていてください
until the numbness goes away.
You should all get
a good night's rest as well.
君たちも きょうは
ゆっくり休んでくれ
I've prepared a room for you to use.
部屋は用意してある
But we've got to find Gaara quickly...
（ナルト）
いや でも 早く我愛羅を…
I'll take advantage of
your kindness, if I may.
（カカシ）
お言葉に甘えさせてもらおう
（ナルト）あ…
We're going on
a harsh march from tomorrow.
（カカシ）どうせ あしたから
強行軍になるんだ
んっ…
I understand...
分かったってばよ
I just have to work hard and
carve out a future for myself.
（我愛羅）努力し
みずから切り開くしかないんだ
And I must not run away
from my path of solitude.
１人きりの孤独な道に逃げず
If I do that, someday...
そうすれば いつか…
Someday... I can be like him...
あいつのように…
Don't order me around!
（我愛羅）ぐずが 俺に指図するな
That's enough outta you!
いい加減にしろ！
I have never thought
of you all as my siblings.
お前らを兄弟と思ったことはない
If you get in my way,
I'll kill you.
邪魔をすれば… 殺す
But now there's something
I understand about the bonds
しかし あいつが あそこまでして言う
つながりとはなんなのか
he went so far to tell me about.
今頃になって 俺にも
少し分かったことがある
I understand that pain,
sadness... and happiness...
苦しみや悲しみ 喜びも
can be shared with others.
ほかの誰かと
分かち合うことができるのだと
うずまきナルト
Uzumaki Naruto...
I learned that through fighting
and getting to know him.
あいつと 戦い触れ合うことで
それを教わった気がする
He knew of the same pain
as me.
あいつは 俺と同じ
苦しみを知っていた
And he taught me that I could
change the path of my life.
そして 生きる道を変えることが
できることを教えてくれた
Uzumaki Naruto...
（カンクロウ）うずまきナルト
Mm?
（ナルト）ん？
Take care of my younger brother...
弟を頼む
フッ 任しとけってばよ
Heh, you can leave it to me.
After all, I am eventually going
to become the Hokage!
俺も いずれ火影になるからな
So I'll do the Kazekage
a favor early on!
今から風影かぜかげに
貸しを作っといてやるよ
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
Aim to remain in active duty
your entire life!
目指せ 生涯現役
Today, the High Achievers Club
きょうの お達者くらぶは
砂隠れのチヨバア様をご紹介します
is pleased to introduce Grandmother Chiyo
of the Hidden Sand.
ふん
Well, to get right to the point,
what are your hobbies?
ずばり ご趣味は？
- Fishing.
- What a simple answer.
釣り
シンプルな お答えです
Well then,
what is your special forte?
では 得意なことは？
- Playing dead.
- Your individuality shines!
死んだふり
個性が光ります
Well next, what are your concerns
at this time?
では今 気になっていることは？
My grandchild.
孫じゃ
Hey, are you watching? Sasori?
おい 見てるか サソリ
ああー！
I'll be the one to punish you!
Wash your neck and wait!
わしが たっぷり可愛がってやる
首を洗って待っておれよ
The Retired Granny's Determination
Next time: The Retired Granny's Determination.
次回「隠居ババアの
決意」
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
木ノ葉の同盟国 砂の忍
The Sand Shinobi, allied nation to the Leaf!
PUPPET MASTER
JUTSU
きょうは 私たちが
特別授業を受け持つ
Today we're presenting a special lesson.
傀儡くぐつの術について
いろいろ教えてやろうじゃん
We're going to teach you all about
the “Puppet Master Jutsu”!
（テマリ）傀儡の術とは
The “Puppet Master Jutsu” allows you
to freely manipulate puppets
指先から出した チャクラの糸で
傀儡を自在に操る術のことだ
with threads of Chakra
that originate from your fingertips.
（カンクロウ）これが
俺のかわいい傀儡たち
These are my cute puppets.
向かって左から 攻撃用の烏からす
From your left; there's Crow for attacking,
Salamander on defense,
防御用 山椒魚さんしょううお
そんで 捕獲用 黒蟻ありだ
and the Black Ant, for capturing!
烏と黒蟻の繰り広げる連携忍術
The combined Ninjutsu deployed by
Crow and the Black Ant
カラクリ演劇
黒秘技機々一発くろひぎききいっぱつは 見たが最後
is the Puppet Show
Secret Black Move Iron Maiden.
Once it starts, it's the last thing you see.
It's the curtain call in no time.
あっという間に終劇しゅうげきじゃん
（テマリ）しかし
いつ見ても不気味な傀儡だな
Still, those puppets are sure creepy,
no matter how many times I see it.
Ha! It's a pity you don't
understand their charm.
（カンクロウ）
はっ この魅力が分からないとは
あわれじゃん
Their poison needles, etc,
are the greatest, aren't they Crow?
この毒針とか最高じゃねえか
なあ 烏
（テマリ）カンクロウ
Kankuro... If you spend all your time
entranced with puppets,
傀儡ばかりに
うつつを抜かしていると
you'll lose your friends...!
友達いなくなるよ
（カンクロウ）えっ あ…
PUPPET MASTER
JUTSU
This ends today's lesson!
これにて きょうの授業は終了
She didn't have to say it like that!
Isn't that so... Crow?
（カンクロウ）
あんな言い方しなくたって
いいじゃねえの
なあ 烏
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.